<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Team name</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Team name</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Team name</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/</link></image><item><title>Approach</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/approach/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/approach/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains key sections of the &lt;strong>Final Report&lt;/strong> for the project focused on the data science methodology used to approach the problem. It should be no more than 3 pages long. It should be done after or in combination with the Requirements document. It should have an initial release after no more than eight weeks into the project, and can serve as an interim project report. It can be refined as the project progresses and the problem is better understood.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-quality">Data Quality&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Describe any steps that were used to address any issues concerning the quality of the data. This may include collecting data quality metrics, discarding subsets of the data, or applying specific techniques for handling missing values, dealing with outliers, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-preprocessing">Data Preprocessing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Describe the steps taken to preprocess the raw data to prepare it for analysis. This may include data transformations to convert to a required format, feature engineering operations, encoding features as binary, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="exploratory-data-analysis-eda">Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discuss any techniques employed to gain insights into the data. This could include data visualizations, generating summary statistics, initial analysis, and other exploratory techniques used to understand the data distributions, features, and helpful patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="model-development">Model Development&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Describe the algorithms, methodology, and architectures used to generate models. Discuss how models were generated, seeded, and improved. Show the libraries and frameworks used for model development, as well as the rationale behind those choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="model-evaluation">Model Evaluation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discuss the evaluation metrics used to assess model performance, and justify those choices based on the problem that the project is addressing. Describe the evaluation techniques used, such as cross-validation, and how undesirable model behaviors, such as overfitting, were avoided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Assessment</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/data/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The dataset used in this project is sourced from the Aviation safety reporting system. The original ASRS dataset has more than 300 thousand rows of information from the year 1988. Since we are specifically interested in runway incursion we applied a filter while downloading the dataset and received a subset of 46,000 rows and 126 columns. The rudimentary goal is to analyse this dataset to identify fracture points in safety regulations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-overview-and-examples">Data Overview and Examples&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The ASRS data is anonymised reports collected from individuals working in the aviation sector. The dataset contains the credentials of the reporting person (excluding personally identifiable content), time and date of the incident, name of the airport, state, altitude, visibility, narrative etc. We intend to use a subset of the 127 features already present with us. The reason is that there are multiple features with a negligible amount of data making analysis unfavourable. Therefore we intend to drop those features completely before further processing. ASRS is the largest data repository available for aviation safety incidents therefore any other dataset which is publicly available may either be a subset of ASRS or might not be reliable since ASRS is a government-backed dataset.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-accessibility">Data Accessibility&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The dataset is accessible through a web portal. There are multiple filters that a user could use to extract the data based on time, type of incident, reporting agency etc. Since we are interested in runway incursions we used word filters like runway, ramp and taxiway. The major constraint for downloading the dataset is at a time only 10,000 rows can be downloaded. Therefore we had to download 5 reports and collate them together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-formats">Data Formats&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The dataset can be downloaded in Excel, CSV, pdf, word and HTML formats from the ASRS portal. For ease of use with Python, we preferred the usage of csv format.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-challenges">Data Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The most challenging part of the dataset is the narrative. The narrative is a description of the incident from a reporter/observer’s point of view. All the reports available in the dataset are not written in aviation English. For instance, airplane, aircraft and flight may essentially point towards the same object but are written in diverse ways. Similarly, the runway is often time written as rwy. All the reports are not written in a professional manner, for instance in a report pilot makes an attempt to humor by mentioning “spilling coffee in the cockpit”. This information is futile as far as the algorithm is concerned.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-visualizations-and-highlights">Data Visualizations and Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Including a visualization is a simple way to show something interesting about the data. Perhaps the visualizations could simply highlight the size, distribution, and other simple statistical characteristics of the data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="https://imgur.com/YUerqmA" alt="Number of incidents regarding light" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="https://imgur.com/2QSREdQ" alt="Number of primary problems" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="https://imgur.com/mh9Q15O" alt="Top 50 airports with most cases" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problem and Requirements</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/problem-statement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/problem-statement/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/11/business/air-traffic-control-austin-airport-fedex-southwest.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">‘Air disasters are rare in the US, close calls are a different story’&lt;/a> The New York Times (Front Page) - 23rd August 2023.
The article highlights a concerning trend of safety incidents and near misses in the United States&amp;rsquo; aviation industry. While there haven&amp;rsquo;t been major plane crashes for over a decade, close calls involving commercial airlines are occurring frequently, often due to human error and a shortage of air traffic controllers.
The number of near misses has doubled in the last decade, raising questions about the safety of the U.S. air travel system. Direct action is needed to improve the situation. NASA maintains a database - ‘Aviation Safety Reporting System’ - that records incident reports of all runway/taxiway incursions since 1988. A treasure trove of untapped potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="motivation">Motivation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The United States alone has an annual passenger traffic of 666 million passengers (in 2021). In recent years aviation safety reporting system has received a record number of incident reports which points to a major question whether the safety standards have been degrading or the number of reports has been increasing. Whatever may be the case there are millions of passengers who travel in these aircraft and therefore it becomes necessary to find out the root causes of these faults.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problem-for-the-semester">Problem for the Semester&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>To analyze aviation incursion reports and determine the primary safety concerns and system fracture points leading to such situations with compelling data.
To improve aviation safety through the analysis of NASA’s ASRS data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To use Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing models to process data and extract useful statistics from (45000, 126) records that can be used to make suggestions to the concerned authorities and effectively alleviate the ongoing crisis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Setup preliminary foundation for development of an encompassing artificial intelligence model that can dynamically read new reports and provide valuable insights.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="state-of-the-art">State of the Art&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Post-air crash-related incidents usually investigation teams have a flight manifest and black box data to uncover the root cause of the incident. Unlike crashes, near misses do not have black box access therefore problem solving completely relies on anonymous reports. Therefore analysis of these reports becomes the only way to solve this problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="design-and-approach">Design and Approach&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If we treat the data as supervised data and divide it into train and test. The primary problem can be treated as a label. Post this divide we intend to run correlation analysis and feature extraction algorithms like principle component analysis, and linear discriminant analysis. Word2vec or term frequency-inverse document frequency (tf-idf) to make narratives into features. Train data over a neural network and test it over a sample set to gauge the accuracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="use-case-scenario">Use Case Scenario&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The end user for this system could be the Federal Aviation Administration, this system could help them in policy framing. After certain modifications, airlines could use it internally for incident report generation and problem-solving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="desired-outcomes-and-benefits">Desired Outcomes and Benefits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Given the timeframe of one semester, we find it realistic to focus on a particular type of incident and study it in detail, therefore we intend to focus on runway incursions and identify the fracture points in the system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Results</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/results/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/results/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains key sections of the &lt;strong>Final Report&lt;/strong> for the project focused on results to date. It should be no more than 2 pages long. An initial draft can be created at any point during the project, and can be refined as the project progresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="system-and-model-performance">System and Model Performance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Show the performance of the best system and model(s) developed, showing clearly the performance metrics and improvements over the baseline system as appropriate. Create visualizations that show clearly these results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="discussion-of-findings">Discussion of Findings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Offer a discussion of the main findings using the system developed. Put the results in the context of the original problem statement and the questions that were posed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discuss any unexpected results, and potential explanations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enumerate (ideally in bullets) the most important findings, and their impact on your project goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="limitations-and-future-work">Limitations and Future Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discuss any limitations of the work to date, how these limitations could be addressed in future work. Discuss what lines of work are most promising given the understanding of the problem and the data gained throughout the project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/meetings/minutes_of_meeting_10_12_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/meetings/minutes_of_meeting_10_12_2023/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="points-discussed-in-the-meeting">Points discussed in the meeting:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Upload data and other useful materials to the github repository for the professors to review&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Focus of Incursions - A classifier model for human errors like confusion, fatigue, etc can be designed which can then be tackled by the Federal Aviation Administration. Hint: To classify the data, we can check for keywords like fatigue, extra hours etc. which are related to &amp;ldquo;overtime&amp;rdquo; in the Narrative column of the ASRS dataset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Doubts:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Weather Element/Visibility&amp;rsquo; Numeric Value Meaning
Ans: The numeric value denotes visibility in miles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Ceiling&amp;rsquo; value meaning and usefulness? 0- completely fogged.
Ans: More the ceiling (height of the clouds), the better is the visibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Flight Phase&amp;rsquo; with multiple phases, eg: Parked; Landing; Landing, etc
Ans: They represent the different stages that the plane went through in during the incident. Some cells have redundant stages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Operating Under FAR Part&amp;rsquo; meaning?
Ans: The Federal Aviation Regulations (FARs) are rules prescribed by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) governing all aviation activities in the United States.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check out the power point presentation that was presented at an ASRS meeting and has 4 factors to identify the incursions. It was shared to us by Prof. Najmedin earlier in the emails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The team can get an award if everyone does a good job and wins the International Society of Air Safety Investigators (ISASI) conference. This year it will be held at Lisbon, Portugal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update the project website with the current work done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="important-links">Important Links:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>ASRS General Report Form: &lt;a href="">https://asrs.arc.nasa.gov/docs/general.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ATSAP Resources: &lt;a href="">https://www.atsapsafety.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DataFirst Website: &lt;a href="">https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/editions/2023-fall/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GitHub Austin incident: &lt;a href="">https://github.com/ckids-datafirst/2023-fall-aviation-safety/blob/main/content/data/news_articles.md&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GitHub Aviation Safety GitHub Repository: &lt;a href="">https://github.com/ckids-datafirst/2023-fall-aviation-safety&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title/><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/template-project-website/people/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mentors">Mentors&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Najmedin Meshkati &lt;a href="mailto:meshkati@usc.edu">meshkati@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Daniel Scalese &lt;a href="mailto:scalese@usc.edu">scalese@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yolanda Gil &lt;a href="mailto:gil@isi.edu">gil@isi.edu&lt;/a> (Researcher at USC Information Science Institute; director of Data Science program at USC)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ulf Hermjakob &lt;a href="mailto:ulf@isi.edu">ulf@isi.edu&lt;/a> (Researcher at USC Information Science Institute; Expertise: NLP)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mino Cha &lt;a href="mailto:minoc@usc.edu">minoc@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Likhit Jha &lt;a href="mailto:ljha@usc.edu">ljha@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shreyas Malewar &lt;a href="mailto:malewar@usc.edu">malewar@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chahita Verma &lt;a href="mailto:cverma@usc.edu">cverma@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ravneet Kaur &lt;a href="mailto:ravneetk@usc.edu">ravneetk@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Abhinav Gupta &lt;a href="mailto:agupta67@usc.edu">agupta67@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Atharva Swami &lt;a href="mailto:aswami@usc.edu">aswami@usc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>