<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meetings | Aviation Safety Project</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Meetings</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><image><url>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Meetings</title><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/</link></image><item><title/><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/mom_09_26_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/mom_09_26_2023/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Try to use Pilot&amp;rsquo;s English for NLP approach in place of spoken and written English&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tenerife disaster 2* 747 collision documentary 2007&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aug 23rd 2023 NY times news paper article&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Future applications - many organizations have databases - &amp;rsquo;lessons learnt'.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Southwest fedex runway incursion animation Austin Texas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn a little about aviation safety&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title/><link>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/mom_10_12_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/2023-fall-aviation-safety/meetings/mom_10_12_2023/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="questions">Questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Are we supposed to make a new project or build upon existing work done by the last team? From the report, we can study that they have taken a lot of the same steps we are working on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can we get access to get their project?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do we need to make a poster or ppt? What is the Mid-term presentation format? Is poster necessary?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Doubts:&lt;br>
 a. ‘Weather Element/Visibility’ Numeric Value Meaning&lt;br>
 b. ‘Ceiling’ value meaning and usefulness? 0- completely fogged&lt;br>
 c. ‘Flight Phase’ with multiple phases, eg: Parked; Landing; Landing, etc&lt;br>
 d. ‘Operating Under FAR Part’ meaning?&lt;br>
 e. How should we handle the same columns for different aircrafts and persons?&lt;br>
 f. Need some direction for where to proceed&lt;br>
 g. The dataset description says that this dataset cannot be used for actual implementation since it is not approved by the FAA.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="points-discussed-in-the-meeting">Points discussed in the meeting:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Upload data and other useful materials to the github repository for the professors to review&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Focus of Incursions - A classifier model for human errors like confusion, fatigue, etc can be designed which can then be tackled by the Federal Aviation Administration. Hint: To classify the data, we can check for keywords like fatigue, extra hours etc. which are related to &amp;ldquo;overtime&amp;rdquo; in the Narrative column of the ASRS dataset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Doubts:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Weather Element/Visibility&amp;rsquo; Numeric Value Meaning
Ans: The numeric value denotes visibility in miles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Ceiling&amp;rsquo; value meaning and usefulness? 0- completely fogged.
Ans: More the ceiling (height of the clouds), the better is the visibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Flight Phase&amp;rsquo; with multiple phases, eg: Parked; Landing; Landing, etc
Ans: They represent the different stages that the plane went through in during the incident. Some cells have redundant stages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;Operating Under FAR Part&amp;rsquo; meaning?
Ans: The Federal Aviation Regulations (FARs) are rules prescribed by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) governing all aviation activities in the United States.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check out the power point presentation that was presented at an ASRS meeting and has 4 factors to identify the incursions. It was shared to us by Prof. Najmedin earlier in the emails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The team can get an award if everyone does a good job and wins the International Society of Air Safety Investigators (ISASI) conference. This year it will be held at Lisbon, Portugal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update the project website with the current work done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="ideas">Ideas:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Classifier model for human errors like confusion, fatigue, etc which can then be tackled by the FAA.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incursion Predictor model that takes some features as inputs like weather, crew size, etc and gives the chance or probability of an incursion happening.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="important-links">Important Links:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>ASRS General Report Form: &lt;a href="">https://asrs.arc.nasa.gov/docs/general.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ATSAP Resources: &lt;a href="">https://www.atsapsafety.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DataFirst Website: &lt;a href="">https://ckids-datafirst.github.io/website/editions/2023-fall/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GitHub Austin incident: &lt;a href="">https://github.com/ckids-datafirst/2023-fall-aviation-safety/blob/main/content/data/news_articles.md&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GitHub Aviation Safety GitHub Repository: &lt;a href="">https://github.com/ckids-datafirst/2023-fall-aviation-safety&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>